For you to so easily forget something I've given you...
（戦場ヶ原(せんじょうがはら)）
私が渡したものを
こうも堂々と忘れていくだなんて
is punishable by death, Araragi-kun.
極刑ものの罪悪よ 阿良々木(あららぎ)くん
Yeah, sorry about that.
（阿良々木）
ああ… 悪かったよ
I'm not going to forgive you, even if you apologize.
（戦場ヶ原）謝っても許さないわ
I did come chasing after you to make fun of you, though.
だから 精いっぱい
なぶってあげようと
思って
追いかけて
きたのだけれど
Did you get hit by a car or something?
車にでも ひかれたのかしら？
There's something over there that resembles your precious bike,
あっちで 阿良々木くんが
とても大切にしていた
自転車らしきものが
大破していたというか
which is pretty beaten up, or should I say, rammed into a telephone pole.
電柱に突き刺さっていたというか
コンボイにでも ひかれないと
あんなことには ならないでしょう
Unless you were hit by a convoy of trucks, how would that happen?
No, I just fell on my own.
いや 僕が１人で転んだだけだよ
I was on the phone, pedaling,
電話しながらペダルをこいでいたら
and I ended up crashing into the telephone pole.
電柱に激突しちゃって
Oh, I see.
あらそう
But for you to crash into a sturdy concrete wall with enough force to destroy it,
けれど
あんな丈夫そうなブロック塀をも
破壊する勢いで激突して
その程度のケガで済むなんて
and end up with merely these wounds,
is rather commendable, Araragi-kun.
阿良々木くん 感心するわ
I assume you don't need an ambulance?
えっと 救急車は
いらないんだっけ？
Yeah, I'll be able to move again after I rest a bit.
（阿良々木）
ああ しばらく休んでりゃ
すぐ動けるようになるさ
I see.
そう　じゃ
そんな阿良々木くんに大サービス
Then, I'll do you a big favor.
Think happy thoughts until you're able to move around again.
動けるようになるまで
幸せな気分でいなさいな
This is a well-made ghost story or even a nightmare tale.
A textbook horror story.
Antique-looking, with a history, no doubt.
What you call a classical one.
If Kanbaru asked me, I'd say that even though inferior to vampires,
the monkey's hand is still a pretty famous item, used in
various media, in different arrangements and ways.
If Kanbaru asked me, I'd say that even though inferior to vampires,
the monkey's hand is still a pretty famous item, used in
various media, in different arrangements and ways.
If Kanbaru asked me, I'd say that even though inferior to vampires,
the monkey's hand is still a pretty famous item, used in
various media, in different arrangements and ways.
If Kanbaru asked me, I'd say that even though inferior to vampires,
the monkey's hand is still a pretty famous item, used in
various media, in different arrangements and ways.
If Kanbaru asked me, I'd say that even though inferior to vampires,
the monkey's hand is still a pretty famous item, used in
various media, in different arrangements and ways.
If Kanbaru asked me, I'd say that even though inferior to vampires,
the monkey's hand is still a pretty famous item, used in
various media, in different arrangements and ways.
If Kanbaru asked me, I'd say that even though inferior to vampires,
the monkey's hand is still a pretty famous item, used in
various media, in different arrangements and ways.
If Kanbaru asked me, I'd say that even though inferior to vampires,
the monkey's hand is still a pretty famous item, used in
various media, in different arrangements and ways.
If Kanbaru asked me, I'd say that even though inferior to vampires,
the monkey's hand is still a pretty famous item, used in
various media, in different arrangements and ways.
If Kanbaru asked me, I'd say that even though inferior to vampires,
the monkey's hand is still a pretty famous item, used in
various media, in different arrangements and ways.
If Kanbaru asked me, I'd say that even though inferior to vampires,
the monkey's hand is still a pretty famous item, used in
various media, in different arrangements and ways.
If Kanbaru asked me, I'd say that even though inferior to vampires,
the monkey's hand is still a pretty famous item, used in
various media, in different arrangements and ways.
If Kanbaru asked me, I'd say that even though inferior to vampires,
the monkey's hand is still a pretty famous item, used in
various media, in different arrangements and ways.
If Kanbaru asked me, I'd say that even though inferior to vampires,
the monkey's hand is still a pretty famous item, used in
various media, in different arrangements and ways.
If Kanbaru asked me, I'd say that even though inferior to vampires,
the monkey's hand is still a pretty famous item, used in
various media, in different arrangements and ways.
And the most important factor
that makes monkey's hand a monkey's hand...
...is that it's said to grant the owner's wishes.
It's said, however, to do it in weird ways.
These two conditions should be present.
So this is an item with history.
The monkey's hand was created in India
by a sage who worked miracles, as a device to teach people
that they should live according to their destiny and if they were
to resist their fate, it would lead to catastrophic results.
by a sage who worked miracles, as a device to teach people
that they should live according to their destiny and if they were
to resist their fate, it would lead to catastrophic results.
by a sage who worked miracles, as a device to teach people
that they should live according to their destiny and if they were
to resist their fate, it would lead to catastrophic results.
by a sage who worked miracles, as a device to teach people
that they should live according to their destiny and if they were
to resist their fate, it would lead to catastrophic results.
by a sage who worked miracles, as a device to teach people
that they should live according to their destiny and if they were
to resist their fate, it would lead to catastrophic results.
by a sage who worked miracles, as a device to teach people
that they should live according to their destiny and if they were
to resist their fate, it would lead to catastrophic results.
by a sage who worked miracles, as a device to teach people
that they should live according to their destiny and if they were
to resist their fate, it would lead to catastrophic results.
by a sage who worked miracles, as a device to teach people
that they should live according to their destiny and if they were
to resist their fate, it would lead to catastrophic results.
Speaking about the three wishes,
my first association was the magic lamp from the "One Thousand
and One Nights", but I didn't remember either the story
or its outcome.
my first association was the magic lamp from the "One Thousand
and One Nights", but I didn't remember either the story
or its outcome.
my first association was the magic lamp from the "One Thousand
and One Nights", but I didn't remember either the story
or its outcome.
my first association was the magic lamp from the "One Thousand
and One Nights", but I didn't remember either the story
or its outcome.
my first association was the magic lamp from the "One Thousand
and One Nights", but I didn't remember either the story
or its outcome.
my first association was the magic lamp from the "One Thousand
and One Nights", but I didn't remember either the story
or its outcome.
my first association was the magic lamp from the "One Thousand
and One Nights", but I didn't remember either the story
or its outcome.
but I didn't remember
either the story
or its outcome.
but I didn't remember
either the story
or its outcome.
but I didn't remember
either the story
or its outcome.
but I didn't remember
either the story
or its outcome.
but I didn't remember
either the story
or its outcome.
Moreover, around the world
such tales
are quite common.
Burn
Chaos
Perhaps the type of story of a man who met a creature capable of fulfilling wishes is
for the people overwhelmed by great unreachable desires.
Typeface used for images: HGP mincho B
Suruga Monkey,
Part Two
Episode 7
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Go on in, Araragi-senpai.
（神原(かんばる)）どうぞ 阿良々木先輩
（阿良々木）うわっ
Sorry, it's a little messy.
（神原）
散らかっていて申し訳ないな
No need to hold back, you know.
遠慮しなくて いいんだぞ？
I really admire that you're sensitive enough to hesitate before entering the room of a girl you barely know,
よく知らない女の子の部屋に
入るのに躊躇(ちゅうちょ)する—
阿良々木先輩の繊細さには
素直に感じ入るが
but it's probably not the best time to be worrying about that.
今は そんな場合でもないだろう
（阿良々木）あ… ああ…
Yeah...
Kanbaru.
（阿良々木）神原
（神原）何だ？
What's up?
One hour-no, thirty minutes is fine...
（阿良々木）
１時間 いや 30分でいいから
Just give me some time to clean up this room.
僕に この部屋を
掃除するための時間をくれ
Okay.
Cleaning
Animation Number 41
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
So,
（神原）
じゃあ さて 何から
話したものかな 阿良々木先輩
where should I start, Araragi-senpai?
Well, at any rate,
まあ とりあえずは
please allow me to apologize for last night.
昨夜のことを
謝らせてもらおうと思う
Yeah...
やっぱり あれは お前だったのか
Like I thought, that was you...
Beast
Animation Number 48
Saying things like "like I thought"
（神原）やっぱりなどと
really makes you sound irritated, Araragi-senpai.
歯がゆい言い方をするのだな
阿良々木先輩は
You completely saw through it, right?
完全に見抜いていたのだろう？
そうでなければ
If you didn't,
then there's no way you'd come to talk to me.
阿良々木先輩のほうから
私を訪ねてくるはずが ないからな
Not really,
（阿良々木）
別に あてずっぽうだよ
it was just a guess.
I came to my conclusion based on your build, outline, and silhouette.
体格とか輪郭とか
REMINISCENCE
シルエットとかでの判断
I also considered who'd know about my study session with Senjougahara.
僕が勉強会で 戦場ヶ原の家に
行くことを知ってたヤツとか
I searched after narrowing it down with those factors.
そういう条件から絞ったうえで
検索をかけて
REMINISCENCE
Limbs
Animation Number 54
If you think of it like that, well, yeah...
そう考えれば… な
Hmm, I see.
ふむ なるほど　卓見だ
Nice insight.
They say that there are guys who can differentiate girls based on their waists...
男子の中には腰の形で
女子を判別できる者がいるというが
can you do that too?
そういう類いの話だろうか？
（阿良々木）うっ
Sorry about that.
すまなかった
That wasn't my intention...
あんなつもりは なかったんだ
Well, even if you apologize...
（阿良々木）
いや 謝ってもらっても…
What I really want to know is the reason.
僕が知りたいのは
むしろ理由のほうなんだけど
Well, actually, even more than the reason, that power...
いや 理由はともかく あの力
I want to ask about that superhuman strength...
怪力のことを聞きたいんだけど
一体 お前…
What exactly do you...
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
ううむ
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Black Scene
I guess if I was to start somewhere,
何から話したものかというなら
やはり その辺りからか
I guess it'd have to be from there...
All right.
そうだな しかし
Araragi-senpai, first I'd like to ask you
阿良々木先輩は
突拍子もないことを
信じることができる
タイプの人間かどうか
if you're the type of person that can believe in things that seem crazy.
最初に質問しておきたいのだが
Things that seem crazy?
突拍子もないこと？
Do you not get it?
分からないだろうか？
Basically, I'm asking if you can believe in what you see with your own eyes.
つまり 阿良々木先輩は
自分の目で見たものを
信じられるかどうか
という意味の質問なのだが
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
I don't believe in anything but what I've seen with my own eyes.
（阿良々木）
僕は自分の目で
見たものしか信じないよ
Vampire
I've come this far believing everything that I've seen.
だから 見たものは全部 信じてきた
Cat
Senjougahara
That includes what happened to Senjougahara, too, of course.
戦場ヶ原のことも もちろんな
Senjougahara
Crab
Oh, you had that figured out too?
何だ そこまでバレていたのか
Senjougahara, from the track and field club, and you, from the basketball club,
（阿良々木）
バスケットボール部のお前と
陸上部の戦場ヶ原とで
were called the Valhalla Combination, right?
合わせて“ヴァルハラコンビ”って
呼ばれてたんだろ？
That's right!
（神原）そのとおりだ
Wow, I'm surprised you even know about that, Araragi-senpai.
そんなことまで
よく知っているな 阿良々木先輩
おみそれしたぞ
I know where it comes from, too.
（阿良々木）由来も聞いたよ
It's a well thought out name.
よく考えられた通り名だよな
Isn't it? I thought of it.
そうだろう　私が考えたのだ
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
She thought of it herself...
（阿良々木）
自分で考えていた
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
It's been a while since I've felt this miserable.
こんな切ない気分
本当に久しぶりだな
But yeah, putting the Valhalla Combination aside,
まあ そうなのだ
ヴァルハラコンビは ともかく
Senjougahara-senpai and I have always, since middle school...
戦場ヶ原先輩と私は中学時代に…
いや その話をするよりも先に
No...
Before I talk anymore about that,
there's something I need you to look at.
先に見ておいてもらいたいものが
あるのだった
Honestly, it's not something I really want others to see.
正直に言って あまり人に
見られたいものでは ないのだ
Girl
Animation Number 89
After all, I am still a girl.
私はこれでも 一応
女の子なのでな
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Well, this is it...
まあ こういうことなのだが
Spirit
REMINISCENCE
It looks like...
猿の手 みたいだ
REMINISCENCE
a monkey's paw...
ほう
Araragi-senpai, you really have unfathomably discerning eyes.
阿良々木先輩は やはり
計り知れないほどの慧眼(けいがん)だな
I'm amazed. Being able to tell what this is with just a glance... there's no word for how surprising that is.
恐れ入った
一見して
これの正体を見抜いてしまうとは
驚きの ひと言に尽きる
（阿良々木）
かっ 勝手に納得するな！
Stop deciding everything I do is impressive!
I'm just telling you my impressions of what I see.
僕は ただ
見たままの感想を述べただけだよ
It's nothing special.
何も見抜いてなんか いない
Oh, really?
そうなのか？
The Monkey's Paw is the title of a short story by William Wymark Jacobs.
「猿(さる)の手(て)」は ウィリアム･
ウイマーク･ジェイコブズの
短編小説のタイトルなのだが
It's said that it grants the owner's wishes, but in a way that conflicts with what they really intended.
持ち主の意に沿わぬ形で
願いをかなえるという
いわくつきのアイテムなんだ
Never heard of it.
全然 知らない
Being able to see the truth behind this without knowing anything,
何も知らないままに
真実を言い当ててしまうなんて
I can't help but think you're chosen by someone in heaven!
阿良々木先輩は
天におわす何者かに
選ばれているとしか思えないな
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
I-Is it okay if I touch it?
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（阿良々木）
さ…
触ってもいいのか？
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Yeah.
（神原）うん 今は別に大丈夫だ
It's fine right now.
I-I see.
（阿良々木）そ… そうか
A living spirit
Animation Number 105
It's alive.
（阿良々木）
生きている
This is the living type of aberration after all.
この怪異(かいい)は やはり
生きているタイプの
怪異だ
（神原）んっ あっ やんっ！
（阿良々木）わっ！
Don't make weird noises!
（阿良々木）変な声をあげんな！
It's because you touched it weirdly!
阿良々木先輩が
変な触り方をするからだ
I did not touch it weirdly!
変な触り方なんて してねえよ
I'm ticklish.
私は くすぐったがりなのだ
Even so, don't make sounds that completely change impressions of you!
だからって いきなり
これまでのキャラを崩すような
声音をあげてんじゃねえよ
Oh, come on.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
As you can see, it moves how I want it to right now,
（神原）
このとおり 今は
思いどおりに動くのだが
but there are times when it won't.
思いどおりに
動かなくなるときが あるのだ
いや 違うな
No, that's not quite right.
I guess I should say it moves against my will.
思いに反して動くようになる
というのだろうか
Against your will?
（阿良々木）
思いに反して？
Well, not really my will, but...
（神原）
いや 思いというか ううん
Hmm, I guess this is hard to understand.
どうも分かりづらいな
In other words, Araragi-senpai,
つまり 阿良々木先輩
the one who attacked you last night was definitely me,
昨晩 阿良々木先輩を襲ったのは
確かに私なのだが
but I have no recollection of it, for the most part.
私には その記憶が
ほとんどないのだ
It was as if I was half asleep, or half dreaming...
夢うつつというか 夢心地というか
It's not like I don't remember it at all, but...
全く覚えていない
わけではないのだが
Trance...
（阿良々木）
トランス
That's called a trance.
トランス状態ってやつだよ それ
知ってる
I know about it.
The type of aberration that manipulates human works by desynchronizing the body and the mind.
人間に憑依(ひょうい)するタイプの怪異は
肉体と精神を
ざくざくに陵辱するから
Wow, you really know a lot, Araragi-senpai.
（神原）
物知りだな 阿良々木先輩は
I see. So it's called an aberration.
そうか 怪異というのか
こういうのは
Well, it's not like I know that much about it either.
（阿良々木）
まあ 僕も とりたてて詳しい
というわけじゃないんだが
I'm not sure why, but lately I've been experiencing things like that a lot.
ただ最近 どうしてなのか
そういう経験をすることが多くて
And there's this guy that knows a lot about that stuff.
それに
そういうのに詳しいヤツがいて
Yeah, I see.
うん　そうか
I'm glad you're an understanding person.
阿良々木先輩が大きな人でよかった
We wouldn't have been able to have this conversation if you'd run away after seeing my arm.
この腕を見せた段階で
逃げ出されでもしていたら
話は できなかったからな
And I probably would've been hurt a little, too.
それに少なからず
傷ついていたと思う
Even so, I really was a bit surprised.
とはいえ さすがに ちょっと
びっくりはしたけどな
But since you told me the most surprising part to start off with,
でも 最初に
いちばん驚かせてくれたから
I'm fairly confident that I won't be surprised by anything you tell me now.
この先 どんなエピソードを
聞いても 驚かない自信があるぜ
Great!
そうか
Of course, that's exactly the reason I showed you my arm first.
もちろん そのために 最初に
この腕を見てもらったのだがな
You got through the most difficult part at the very beginning.
いちばん大変なことを
いちばん最初に済ませたのだ
All right, I think I'll get on to the real topic then.
じゃあ いよいよ
本題に入らせてもらおうと思う
I'm a lesbian.
私はレズなのだ
I guess that might've been a bit blunt, since you're a guy.
阿良々木先輩は男だから
今のでは
少し言葉が露骨だったかな
Umm...
え〜と 言い直そう
Let me rephrase it: I'm a homose-
（神原）私は百合なのだ
（阿良々木）一緒だ そんなもん！
Those are exactly the same!
Wait, what?! What do you mean?
えっ なに？ どういうこと？
You're saying that you and Senjougahara were known as the Valhalla Combination in middle school,
戦場ヶ原と中学時代に
ヴァルハラコンビとか言って？
and Senjougahara refers to you as that girl,
先輩後輩で？
戦場ヶ原は神原のことを
“あの子”とか言って？
and she said yesterday that she'd never broken up with a guy before...
ええ？ 昨日言ってた
“男と別れたことがない”
っていうの ひょっとして
そういう意味だったのか？
Are you saying that you mean...?!
（神原）それは違う
That's not it.
Senjougahara-senpai was my unrequited love.
戦場ヶ原先輩のことは
私の 一方的な片思いだったんだ
To me, Senjougahara-senpai is pure and perfect.
私にとって 戦場ヶ原先輩は
REMINISCENCE
純粋にパーフェクトで
憧れの先輩だったからな
She was someone I adored.
Thoughts
Animation Number 144
I was satisfied by just being near her.
Thoughts
Animation Number 144
そばにいるだけで
満足だったんだ
Thoughts
Animation Number 144
（阿良々木）あ…
Senjougahara-senpai was popular with everyone,
（神原）
戦場ヶ原先輩は
みんなの人気者だったけれど
but I think my feelings stood apart compared to those people.
私の戦場ヶ原先輩に対する思いは
その中でも
一線を画していたように思う
I'm confident about that.
その自負はある
I even thought that I could die for Senjougahara-senpai's sake.
戦場ヶ原先輩のためなら
死んでもいいとすら思っていたのだ
But...
けれど 戦場ヶ原先輩は
変わってしまっていた
Senjougahara-senpai changed.
She became different
Animation Number 148
She became different.
She became different
Animation Number 148
変わり果てていた
She became different
Animation Number 148
I'd heard that she fell ill after she got to high school.
高校生になってから 重い病気を
患ったということは聞いていた
I'd also heard that she stopped track and field because of a prolonged illness.
長患いで 陸上を
やめてしまったことも聞いていた
But I'd never have thought she'd change that much.
でも あそこまで
変わってしまっているとは
思いもしなかった
I thought it was just a bad rumor.
悪い噂(うわさ)だと思っていた
But I was wrong.
しかし 違った
It was even worse than the rumor.
そんな噂どころじゃなかった
There was something much more alarming happening to her body.
戦場ヶ原先輩の体には
もっと大変なことが起きていた
Once I realized that, I knew I had to do something.
私は それに気が付いて
“何とかしなければ”と思った
I knew I had to save her.
“戦場ヶ原先輩を助けなければ”
と思った
It's natural, don't you agree?
だって そうだろう？
We were in different clubs and different classes in middle school,
中学生のころ
学年も部活も違ったけれど
but she treated me really kindly.
戦場ヶ原先輩は
私に とても優しくしてくれたんだ
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
So, this time,
だから 今度は
私が戦場ヶ原先輩を助けようとした
I was the one who tried to save her.
I could do something about her problem.
戦場ヶ原先輩の抱えているものを
私が 何とかできる
Even if I couldn't, I could be by her side and heal her heart.
それができなくても
そばにいるだけで
Heavy
Animation Number 157
戦場ヶ原先輩の心を
癒すことができる
Heavy
Animation Number 157
Thoughts
That's what I thought.
Animation Number 157
Thoughts
そう思っていた
Animation Number 157
Thoughts
I was hopelessly rejected.
それは取りつく島もなく拒絶された
"I don't even think of you as an underclassman, let alone as a friend."
“あなたのことなんて
友達とも思っていなければ”
“後輩とも思っていない
今も昔も”
"Not now and not ever."
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
She said that clearly to me.
そんなことを はっきり言われた
Monologue
Animation Number 160
So from then on, I've kept my distance from her.
Monologue
Animation Number 160
だから 私は それ以来
Monologue
Animation Number 160
戦場ヶ原先輩には
近づかなかった
Monologue
Animation Number 160
（阿良々木）あ…
Since that was the one and only thing she had ever wanted from me...
それが 戦場ヶ原先輩が私に望んだ
唯一のことだったからな
Of course, I couldn't forget about her...
もちろん 戦場ヶ原先輩のことを
忘れることなんて
できるわけがなかったけれど でも
But if that would save her even the tiniest bit,
それで 少しでも戦場ヶ原先輩が
救われるというのなら
then I could accept it.
それを私は よしとできる
お前…
You...
But a year went by, and I found out about you.
でも １年が たって
REMINISCENCE
私は阿良々木先輩のことを
知ってしまった
REMINISCENCE
You were talking to her one morning quite closely in the classroom.
戦場ヶ原先輩は
阿良々木先輩と朝の教室で
蝶々喃々(ちょうちょうなんなん)と話していた
Even during middle school, she'd never talked to me with that kind of...
中学時代でも私に
見せてくれたことがないような
REMINISCENCE
幸せそうな笑顔でな
happy smile.
REMINISCENCE
分かるか？
Do you get it?!
You were doing something that I really, really wanted to do, but had given up on
阿良々木先輩は
私が したくてしたくて
でも できずに諦めていたことを
Kanbaru!
like it was perfectly natural!
（神原）まるで当然のように
（阿良々木）神原…
Love
A
（神原）
やっていたのだ
Love
（阿良々木）いや それは
No, that was...
Change, silence
Animation Number 180
At first, I was jealous.
Change, silence
Animation Number 180
（神原）
最初は嫉妬した
Change, silence
Animation Number 180
I tried to rethink my feelings,
途中で思い直そうとして
最後まで嫉妬した
but in the end, I was still jealous of you.
I wondered why I wasn't good enough.
どうして私じゃダメなのかと思った
男だったらいいのかと思った
I wondered if it would be different if I were a guy.
私が女だからダメなのかと思った
I wondered if it was because I was a girl.
Maybe she didn't need an underclassman or even a friend,
友達や後輩は いらないけれど
恋人なら よかったのかと
but wanted a lover.
If that was the case, why couldn't it be me?!
だったら
私でも いいはずじゃないか！
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
I've already become absolutely inhuman.
I was jealous of you, and I was disappointed with her.
阿良々木先輩に嫉妬して
戦場ヶ原先輩に失望した
I've already become absolutely inhuman.
And I was on the verge of giving up on someone like myself.
そして
そんな自分自身に あきれ果てた
I've already become absolutely inhuman.
To hell with healing her pain... to hell with keeping my distance from her...
何が“戦場ヶ原先輩を癒す”だ
何が“身を引く”だ
I've already become absolutely inhuman.
Was I seriously thinking that she was going to praise me for doing that?!
そうしていれば 戦場ヶ原先輩に
I've already become absolutely inhuman.
褒めてもらえるとでも
思っていたのか？
I've already become absolutely inhuman.
That's ridiculous!
バカバカしい　偽善にも程がある
I've already become absolutely inhuman.
How could I be that hypocritical?!
But...
でも それでも
Even then...
I wanted her to treat me kindly like she used to...
私は昔みたいに
戦場ヶ原先輩に
優しくしてもらいたかったのだ
Maybe it's just selfish, but I want to be near her no matter what.
エゴでも何でも 戦場ヶ原先輩の
そばにいたい だから…
So that's why...
Girl
Animation Number 193
So that's why I asked this paw to grant my wish.
Girl
Animation Number 193
だから 私は
この手に願ったんだ
Girl
Animation Number 193
Left hand
Beast
Animation Number 193
I want to be by her side.
Beast
Animation Number 193
戦場ヶ原先輩の
そばにいたい… と
Beast
Animation Number 193
Monkey
Bakemonogatari
Next, commercials
So that person's name is Oshino Meme?
（神原）
で その人は
忍野(おしの)メメという名前なのか？
Is "Meme" written in katakana?
メメは片仮名でいいのか？
Yeah.
（阿良々木）ああ
Although, he's not as cute as his name suggests.
とはいえ 名前ほど
かわいらしいヤツじゃないぞ
If we don't hurry, the sun will set before we get there.
本当に早くしないと
そろそろ日が暮れてしまいそうだな
Your left hand is dangerous at night, right?
夜になったらヤバいんだろ？
その左手
Yeah, though really, it's actually that there's no problem when the sun is out.
逆に言えば 日のあるうちは
問題がないということだ
At least for the next few hours, it should be fine.
少なくとも あと数時間くらいは
確実に大丈夫だな
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Araragi-senpai, there's one thing I want to ask you.
（神原）
阿良々木先輩
１つ 聞きたいことが あるんだが
何だ？
What is it?
What part of Senjougahara-senpai captivated you?
（神原）
阿良々木先輩は
戦場ヶ原先輩のどういうところに
引かれたのだろうか？
I mean, she was your classmate for over two years, and you guys never even talked.
２年以上 口も利いたことのない
ただのクラスメートだった
というのに
ど… どうして
そんなこと聞くんだよ？
W-Why would you ask that?
うん　つまりだな
In other words, if you're after her body, I think I can be of service instead.
もしも 阿良々木先輩が
戦場ヶ原先輩の体が目当てなら
私が代われると思うのだ
（阿良々木）な…
I think I'm fairly cute.
私は そこそこ かわいいと思うのだ
She said it herself
Animation Number 212
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
If I let my hair grow a little bit, I think I'd be a bit more girly,
髪の毛を伸ばせば
もう少し女の子らしくなると思うし
and I also maintain my skin well.
肌ツヤも きれいに保っている
Plus, I've been playing sports for a long time.
それに 昔から
スポーツをやっているからな
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
My waist is just narrow enough, and my body is nice and tight overall.
（神原）
ウエストの辺りなんか
程よく くびれて
引き締まった
いい体をしているのだ
（阿良々木）はっ え…
I'm completely serious.
（神原）私の覚悟は本物だぞ
If you wish so,
阿良々木先輩が求めるのなら
いつでも どこでも
I'll be the bottom to your top anytime, anywhere.
阿良々木先輩の攻めを
受けきるつもりは ある
Top...?! Bottom...?!
攻め？ 受け？
Why the hell would I wish for that?!
なんで僕が そんなもんを
求めなくちゃならないんだ！
It got bigger
Animation Number 223
ん？ ああ そうか
Oh, I see. You don't know anything about BL.
阿良々木先輩は
ＢＬの素養がないのか　意外だな
That's surprising.
I don't want to talk about BL with an underclassman girl!
（阿良々木）
後輩の女子とＢＬの話とか
したくねえよ！
Animation Number 223
ん？ ＢＬとは
ボーイズラブの略だぞ？
BL is short for boys' love, you know.
Animation Number 226
I know! I'm not misunderstanding you!
（阿良々木）
知っている！
そこで勘違いは していない！
Yeah, I noticed it when I was cleaning her room.
ああ 気付いては いたさ
神原の部屋を片づけたときに
REMINISCENCE
Homophile
You're not misunderstanding me?
（神原）勘違いは していないのか
Then, what exactly are you angry about, Araragi-senpai?
ならば 阿良々木先輩は 今
一体全体
何に怒っているのだろう？
Don't tell me you like the bottom!
ひょっとして
阿良々木先輩は“受け”なのか？
Shut up!
（阿良々木）
うるさい この話は もう終わりだ！
This conversation is over!
Forgive me for being intrusive, Araragi-senpai,
（神原）
恐れながら 差し出がましいことを
言わせていただくが 阿良々木先輩
but I think that you won't survive in the world
後輩の女子と
お下劣な会話を楽しめないようでは
if you can't even enjoy a dirty conversation with an underclassman girl.
社会に出てから
やっていけないと思うぞ？
I really don't want to be counseled by an underclassman girl.
（阿良々木）
それこそ
後輩の女子に諭されたくないよ
Even if you say that, Araragi-senpai,
（神原）
そうはいってもな 阿良々木先輩
it's problematic that you desire chaste girls when that desire is based on unfounded fantasies.
そのような
薄っぺらい女性幻想に基づいて
貞淑であることを求められても
挨拶に困るぞ
It can't be helped.
しかたあるまい
Even girls are interested in talking about dirty stuff.
女の子だって
エッチな話に興味があるのだ
（阿良々木）ハア…
Back to main story
Animation Number 235
All right, you can go ahead and continue telling me whether you wear boxers or briefs.
さあ それでは
阿良々木先輩は
Animation Number 236
ブリーフ派か
トランクス派か
Animation Number 236
という話を
続けようではないか
I never said anything about that.
そんな話は していなかったぞ！
What?
あれ？
私がスパッツの下に
Animation Number 238
Were we talking about whether or not I'm wearing panties under my spats?
パンツを
はいているかどうか
という話だったか？
It became even bigger
Animation Number 242
Aren't you wearing them?! Kanbaru-san!
はいてないんですか 神原さん？
Animation Number 244
じゃ じゃあ そのスカートから
はみ出しているスパッツの下は…
So under the spats coming out from the bottom of your skirt is...
Maiden's hidden nectar
Animation Number 246
Even if that was the case, there's no need to be surprised, is there?
たとえ そうだったとしても
驚くほどのことでは ないだろう
Animation Number 248
Spats were originally intended to be lingerie, you know.
スパッツというのは
もともと
[ Meaning ]
Tight pants.
Animation Number 248
肌着の一種だからな
That's all the more of a reason!
だったら なおさら より一層だ！
Isn't that the same as flashing your underwear around every day?!
常にパンツ 見せびらかしながら
Animation Number 251
生活してるようなもんじゃねえか
それ！
Hmm, if you put it that way, I suppose it's true.
（神原）
ふむ　そう言われれば
そのとおりなのだが
Well, I guess for the time being
まあ その辺りは さしずめ
we'll just say it was a stylish present from this sports-loving girl.
スポーツ少女からの
小粋な贈り物といったところだな
No!
（阿良々木）
違う 露出狂の変態行為だ！
That's just plain exhibitionist perversion!
Oh yeah, now I remember!
（神原）ああ そうだ 思い出した
That's not what we were talking about either.
そんな話もしていなかったぞ
We were talking about whether I could be Senjougahara-senpai's replacement.
私が戦場ヶ原先輩の代わりに
なれるかどうかと
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Hold it!
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（阿良々木）
待て 事の真相を
はっきりさせないままに
Don't change subjects before stating it clearly!
話を戻そうとするな！
Animation Number 262
Are you wearing them, or aren't you?!
本当は はいているのか
それとも本当に はいていないのか
Animation Number 264
Say it clearly!
ちゃんと明言するんだ！
Let's not concern ourselves with such vulgar details, Araragi-senpai.
（神原）
そういう下卑(げび)た事情は
割愛しようではないか
阿良々木先輩
Animation Number 264
It's a trivial matter.
ささいなことだ
Like hell it is!
Koyomi
Animation Number 270
（阿良々木）
ささいじゃねえ！
My
Animation Number 271
It's the difference between my underclassman being a sports girl or an exhibitionist!
僕の後輩がスポーツ少女か
露出狂かの分水嶺(ぶんすいれい)だ！
girl
Animation Number 273
Suruga
Animation number 274
Clearly distinguish
Animation Number 275
Let's see...
（神原）
そうだな
Animation Number 277
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
What if you think of if this way:
Suruga Kanbaru
では こう考えたら どうだろう
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Koyomi Araragi
girl
Animation Number 280
She's both a sports girl and an exhibitionist.
スポーツ少女でもあり
また露出狂でもある
Koyomi
Animation Number 281
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Exhibitionist
Animation Number 280
Either.
Animation Number 283
girl
Animation Number 285
For someone who believes she's a sports girl, she is a sports girl,
スポーツ少女だと
思う者には
A
RARA
GI
KOYOMI
Animation number 286
A
RARA
GI
KOYOMI
Animation number 286
A
RARA
GI
KOYOMI
Animation number 286
A
RARA
GI
KOYOMI
Animation number 286
A
RARA
GI
KOYOMI
Animation number 286
A
RARA
GI
KOYOMI
Animation number 286
A
RARA
GI
KOYOMI
Animation number 286
A
RARA
GI
KOYOMI
Animation number 286
A
RARA
GI
KOYOMI
Animation number 286
A
RARA
GI
KOYOMI
Animation number 286
A
RARA
GI
KOYOMI
Animation number 286
A
RARA
GI
KOYOMI
Animation number 286
A
RARA
GI
KOYOMI
Animation number 286
A
RARA
GI
KOYOMI
Animation number 286
A
RARA
GI
KOYOMI
Animation number 286
A
RARA
GI
KOYOMI
Animation number 286
A
RARA
GI
KOYOMI
Animation number 286
A
RARA
GI
KOYOMI
Animation number 286
girl
Animation Number 285
スポーツ少女であり
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Exhibitionist
Animation Number 288
and for someone who believes she's an exhibitionist, she's an exhibitionist.
Exhibitionist
Animation Number 288
露出狂だと思う者には
露出狂なのだ
Exhibitionist
Animation Number 288
For those who think...
Animation Number 289
Exhibitionist
Animation Number 291
Cogito ergo sum
Animation Number 289
In words
Animation Number 294
Don't play with words!
In words
Animation Number 294
（阿良々木）
言葉で遊ぶな！
In words
Animation Number 294
Koyomi
Animation Number 295
I can be either
Animation Number 296
It's both A and B.
I can be either
Animation Number 296
〝〇〇(まるまる)でもあり
××(ばつばつ)でもある〞
I can be either
Animation Number 296
A or B
Animation Number 297
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Suruga
Animation Number 281
For someone who believes it's A, it's A,
Suruga
Animation Number 281
〝〇〇だと思う者には
〇〇で〞
Suruga
Animation Number 281
As A.
Animation Number 299
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
As B.
Animation Number 300
and for someone who believes it's B, it's B.
As B.
Animation Number 300
〝××だと思う者には
××だ〞
As B.
Animation Number 300
Suruga Kanbaru
Koyomi Araragi
っていうセリフが
かっこいいのは
Cool
Animation Number 303
Until middle school!
Animation Number 304
That's only cool until middle school!
Until middle school!
Animation Number 304
中学生までだ
Until middle school!
Animation Number 304
Jeez
Animation Number 305
Koyomi
Animation Number 306
Are you my little sister or something?!
Koyomi
Animation Number 306
お前は僕の妹か！
Koyomi
Animation Number 306
Animation number 306
Koyomi
A
R
G
I
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
But seriously, Kanbaru, no matter how hard you try,
（阿良々木）でもな 神原
真面目な話
どんなに頑張ったところで
you can never be a replacement for Senjougahara.
お前じゃ
戦場ヶ原の代わりには なれないよ
You're not Senjougahara.
お前は戦場ヶ原じゃないしな
It's impossible for someone to replace someone else.
誰かが誰かの代わりになんて
なれるわけが ないし
Just like it's impossible for someone to become someone else.
誰かが誰かに なれるわけなんか
ねえんだよ
No matter how much you like them...
いくら好きでも いくら憧れても
No matter how much you adore them.
That's true.
そうだな
阿良々木先輩の言うとおりだ
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
It's just as you said.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Yeah.
（阿良々木）ああ
All right, let's stop with the idle talk and get going already.
じゃあ ムダ口たたいてないで
もう行こうぜ
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（阿良々木）ん？
Shinobu Oshino
Animation Number 244
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
H-Hey, Araragi-senpai,
（神原）
な… なあ 阿良々木先輩
何だ？ あの子
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
what was with that girl?
She was super cute!
めちゃくちゃ かわいかったな！
ん… 今日いちばんの笑顔で
何を言ってるんだ お前は！
Why does that give you the biggest smile you've had all day?
I want to hug her.
抱きしめたい… いや 抱かれたい！
No, I want her to hug me!
ハア… でも まあ
But anyway, you're better off not getting involved with that.
あれには関わらないほうが いいよ
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
You're late, Araragi-kun!
（忍野）遅いよ 阿良々木くん
I was so tired of waiting that I was about to fall asleep.
待ちくたびれて
もう少しで寝ちまうところだった
What's this, Araragi-kun?
何だい 阿良々木くん
I see you brought yet a different girl today.
今日は
また違う女の子を連れているんだね
You bring a different girl every time I see you.
君は会うたんびに
違う女の子を連れているなあ
I'm happy for you.
全く ご同慶の至りだよ
Shut up.
（阿良々木）
うるせえ
同じセリフを何度も言うな
Stop saying the same thing every time I come.
Oh yeah, I saw Shinobu on the stairway.
そうだ 忍(しのぶ)を階段で見かけたぜ
What's she doing out there?
なんで あいつ
あんな所にいるんだ？
Oh, she sulked off when I ate one of the donuts from Mister Donut.
ああ おやつのミスタードーナツを
僕が１個 多く食べたら
忍ちゃん すねちゃってさ
Animation Number 388
She's been like that since yesterday.
昨日から ずっと
あんな調子なんだよ
What kind of vampire is she?
どんな吸血鬼だよ…
Oshino, this is Kanbaru Suruga, one year behind me in school.
忍野 １個下の後輩で神原駿河(するが)だ
Kanbaru is written with the characters god and plains.
“かんばる”は神様の“神”に
原っぱの“原”
God
Animation Number 341
Plains
“原”って書いて
“ばる”って読むんだ
As for Suruga, um...
駿河は… えっと
It's Suruga from Japanese bondage torture.
“駿河問(するがど)い”の駿河だ
Japanese bondage torture
Animation Number 343
Oh, Japanese bondage torture, huh?
ああ 駿河問いね
分かった分かった
Got it, got it.
Scream~
Animation Number 344
I'm Araragi-senpai's underclassman. Nice to meet you.
阿良々木の後輩だ　初めまして
Nice to meet you, too.
初めまして
忍野メメです お嬢さん
I'm Oshino Meme, miss.
ふうん
阿良々木くんの後輩ってことは
If you're his underclassman, then you should also be an underclassman of that tsundere girl, am I right?
ツンデレちゃんの後輩でも
あるんだね
Oshino, anyway, I'll start off by giving this to you.
（阿良々木）
忍野 とりあえず まずは
これ 渡しとくよ
It's from that tsundere girl, Senjougahara.
そのツンデレちゃん
戦場ヶ原からだ
Oh right, money.
ん？ ああ お金ね　お金お金
Money, money...
That's great.
よかった よかった
It was just about to start affecting my lifestyle.
そろそろ
生活に困ってきていたんだよ
So, what's up with that young lady?
で そのお嬢ちゃんは何なのかな？
Oh, it's those bandages, isn't it?
ああ その包帯かな？
へえ…
Oshino-san, I'm...
忍野さん 私は…
Let's start from the beginning.
順番に聞こうか
It doesn't really seem to be an enjoyable story.
あんまり楽しい話じゃなさそうだ
Stories about arms never are.
腕に絡む腕話は
いつも そうなんだよ
It's especially true in my case, and all the more if it's the left arm.
この僕の場合はね
ましてや それが左手ともなると
もう なおさらさ
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Could you take off the bandages and let me see it, miss?
（忍野）
包帯ほどいて見せてくれるかな？
お嬢ちゃん
Oh, sure.
Gazing
Animation Number 358
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Is this good enough?
これでいいのか
Yup, it is.
（忍野）
うん いいよ　そっか やっぱりね
I see, just as I thought.
Araragi-kun, and you too, miss... let me clear something up for you:
阿良々木くん それにお嬢ちゃん
最初に 勘違いを
正しておいてあげよう
Your left hand-that's not a monkey's paw.
お嬢ちゃんの左手
それはね 猿の手じゃないよ
Huh?
（阿良々木）は？
（神原）は…
The monkey's paw assimilating with the owner
（忍野）
猿の手が持ち主の腕と
一本化しちゃうなんて例
is something that I've never heard of.
僕は寡聞にして聞いたことがない
Miss, your hand was originally mummified, right?
お嬢ちゃん その手は
もともとはミイラだったんだっけ？
If that has gained life by assimilating with you,
それが
お嬢ちゃんと同化することによって
生命を得たとなると
then I'd say for the time being that it's probably the Rainy Devil.
Animation Number 336
さしずめ〝レイニー･
デビル〞かな
Animation Number 336
Rainy?
“レイニー”？
Yeah, it's a low-level demon.
そう 低俗な悪魔さ
If you narrow that group down to ones that have a monkey's arms and wear a raincoat,
その中でも猿の腕を持つ
雨がっぱの悪魔となれば
the number necessarily decreases quite a bit.
必然 数は限られてくる
The only one that assimilates with the owner is the Rainy Devil.
持ち主と 一体化するってのは
レイニー･デビルだ
It's not a monkey's paw-it's a demon's hand.
猿の手じゃない 悪魔の手だ
Of course, it will grant you anything you wish for...
そりゃあ 何でも かなえてくれるさ
I mean, after all, it's a trade for your soul.
だって 魂と引き換えなんだから
Your soul?
魂…
In exchange for taking your soul it grants you three wishes
Animation Number 374
In exchange for taking your soul it grants you three wishes.
In exchange for taking your soul it grants you three wishes
Animation Number 374
（忍野）
魂と引き換えに
In exchange for taking your soul it grants you three wishes
Animation Number 374
３つの願いを
かなえてやろう
In exchange for taking your soul it grants you three wishes
Animation Number 374
It's only natural.
当たり前のことさ 悪魔なら
For demons, that is...
Bakemonogatari
Monkey.
Suruga Monkey, Part Two
Bakemonogatari
Monkey.
Suruga Monkey, Part Two
Bakemonogatari
Monkey.
Suruga Monkey, Part Two
Bakemonogatari
Monkey.
Suruga Monkey, Part Two
Bakemonogatari
Monkey.
Suruga Monkey, Part Two
CONTINUED NEXT TIME
（火憐）火憐だぜ！
（月火）月火だよ！
I'm Karen!
And I'm Tsukihi!
（火憐）
月火ちゃんって茶道部だよな？
Tsukihi-chan, you're in the tea club, right?
（月火）
うん 月火ちゃんって茶道部だよ！
Yeah, I am the tea club!
Well then, do you know what type of tea they use in Uji city in Kyoto?
（火憐）
じゃあ 京都の宇治市が
お茶の産地だって知ってる？
（月火）
知ってる知ってる！
I know, I know!
In Uji they have tea on tap!
（火憐）
その宇治市には
お茶の出る蛇口が あるそうだぜ
（月火）
本当に？
Really?
By the way, a tap and a jacuzzi resemble each other in the position of their names, eh?
（火憐）
ところで 蛇口とジャグジーって
名前もポジションも似てるよな
You're well-versed in discussing Uji City.
（月火）
宇治市の話をもっと詳しく！
（火憐）予告編クイズ！
（月火）クイズ！
It's preview quiz!
Quiz!
（火憐）予告編 伊豆
（月火）伊豆？
Preview Izu!
Izu?
Izu is a riddle!
（火憐）伊豆は謎だぜ
（月火）伊豆は謎なの？
Izu is a riddle?
（火憐･月火）
次回「するがモンキー
其ノ参(そのさん)」
Next time, "Suruga Monkey", Part Three!
Next Time
Suruga Monkey, Part Three
（火憐）
伊豆 is クイズ
Izu is a quiz!
Enigmatic!
（月火）
謎めいた！